{"sourceUrl": "https://hub.jhu.edu/2020/03/30/andrew-pekosz-immunity-seasonality/?fbclid=IwAR2LUcjr7Ltz6koe0IjRV3gr7E3tW0K6hqlcaYPtKQz3HBmjlQ7YRGrtgHw", "sourceName": "JHU HUB", "sourceDate": 1585590600.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1585590600.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586381100.040776, "questionText": "What do we know so far about immunity and COVID-19?", "answerText": "Often, there are comparisons between COVID-19 and influenza because the symptoms are somewhat similar and because COVID-19 started to emerge in the winter, which is the same time of the year when we see influenza. But when it comes to immunity, there's a very big difference between influenza and COVID-19. With influenza, because of previous infections and vaccinations, there's always a percentage of the population that is immune to infection—so they're protected and won't get the flu that year. And there's an even larger percentage of the population that has some immunity—not perfect immunity, so you'll still get infected, but enough so that your symptoms will be relatively mild.", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "66f7d71e-79df-11ea-9a15-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "66f7d87e-79df-11ea-acfe-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "66f7d8ec-79df-11ea-8a9c-8c85901aafa7", "topic": "self-quarantine"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://hub.jhu.edu/2020/03/30/andrew-pekosz-immunity-seasonality/?fbclid=IwAR2LUcjr7Ltz6koe0IjRV3gr7E3tW0K6hqlcaYPtKQz3HBmjlQ7YRGrtgHw", "sourceName": "JHU HUB", "sourceDate": 1585590600.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1585590600.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586381100.0413802, "questionText": "Why is it that older people are developing more severe symptoms than younger people, even though both groups have no immunity to COVID-19?", "answerText": "We don't have a good answer for that yet. It certainly seems that people over the age of 60, particularly those with secondary medical conditions, are at greater risk for severe disease. We're beginning to understand that men may also be at increased risk. We're seeing these trends pretty consistently across different countries. What we don't know yet is why. That's a really important area of research that my colleagues at Hopkins are working on. If we could better understand what's happening in high-risk populations to make them more susceptible, it could inform development of treatments for severe disease.", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "66f7ee90-79df-11ea-9799-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "66f7ef6c-79df-11ea-b4e2-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "66f7efd0-79df-11ea-82fb-8c85901aafa7", "topic": "self-quarantine"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://hub.jhu.edu/2020/03/30/andrew-pekosz-immunity-seasonality/?fbclid=IwAR2LUcjr7Ltz6koe0IjRV3gr7E3tW0K6hqlcaYPtKQz3HBmjlQ7YRGrtgHw", "sourceName": "JHU HUB", "sourceDate": 1585590600.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1585590600.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586381100.0420978, "questionText": "What's the role of seasonality in the spread of this virus?", "answerText": "A lot of respiratory viruses have a seasonality. In areas that have seasons, you often see more respiratory disease in the winter than in the summer. That's because the conditions of lower temperature and lower humidity help facilitate transmission of the virus. COVID-19 is entering the population during the winter but we don't know if it's going to act like a typical respiratory virus in terms of seasonality. We don't know if COVID-19 will be very dependent on winter to effectively transmit, like the flu, or if it will find ways to effectively transmit throughout the year.", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "66f80af6-79df-11ea-91df-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "66f80f92-79df-11ea-91c6-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "66f81078-79df-11ea-8c97-8c85901aafa7", "topic": "self-quarantine"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://hub.jhu.edu/2020/03/30/andrew-pekosz-immunity-seasonality/?fbclid=IwAR2LUcjr7Ltz6koe0IjRV3gr7E3tW0K6hqlcaYPtKQz3HBmjlQ7YRGrtgHw", "sourceName": "JHU HUB", "sourceDate": 1585590600.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1585590600.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586381100.0429618, "questionText": "Are you concerned that we'll see a dip in cases this summer and then see a resurgence next fall or winter?", "answerText": "I think that's a major concern. Nearer term, I'm concerned about what will happen if public health interventions are loosened. Right now, public health interventions are doing a good job of reducing the number of cases, but we don't know how long we will have to keep those measures in place. When we relieve them, there is always a potential for cases to spike again.", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "66f82c52-79df-11ea-848c-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "66f82d2e-79df-11ea-9a6c-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "66f82d92-79df-11ea-bed8-8c85901aafa7", "topic": "self-quarantine"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://hub.jhu.edu/2020/03/30/andrew-pekosz-immunity-seasonality/?fbclid=IwAR2LUcjr7Ltz6koe0IjRV3gr7E3tW0K6hqlcaYPtKQz3HBmjlQ7YRGrtgHw", "sourceName": "JHU HUB", "sourceDate": 1585590600.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1585590600.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586381100.043426, "questionText": "In addition to better understanding immunity and seasonality, what other aspects of COVID-19 are researchers trying to understand?", "answerText": "We're trying to understand how this virus is able to cause many more cases of mild disease compared to other viruses. We think that may be linked to why it's so good at transmitting. We're also trying to understand, once you've had the virus, whether you're safe to go out and work again because you have some level of protection.", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "66f83e68-79df-11ea-a9f3-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "66f83f1c-79df-11ea-8ee4-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "66f83f80-79df-11ea-8cae-8c85901aafa7", "topic": "self-quarantine"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://hub.jhu.edu/2020/03/30/andrew-pekosz-immunity-seasonality/?fbclid=IwAR2LUcjr7Ltz6koe0IjRV3gr7E3tW0K6hqlcaYPtKQz3HBmjlQ7YRGrtgHw", "sourceName": "JHU HUB", "sourceDate": 1585590600.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1585590600.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586381100.0440261, "questionText": "How can people who have recovered from COVID-19 help researchers to understand immunity, seasonality, and other aspects of the virus?", "answerText": "We need people to volunteer after they've recovered to help us understand how their bodies have responded to the infection. Those types of studies are going to be so important because as we, hopefully, flatten the curve, we may have the opportunity to help people at the tail-end of the curve improve their prognosis based on findings from our study of people who were infected on the front-end of the curve.", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "66f855e2-79df-11ea-9feb-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "66f856b4-79df-11ea-9749-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "66f8572c-79df-11ea-827b-8c85901aafa7", "topic": "self-quarantine"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://hub.jhu.edu/2020/03/23/how-to-self-quarantine-self-isolate/?mc_cid=0ed1a231a3&mc_eid=9687fd9d33", "sourceName": "JHU HUB", "sourceDate": 1584979200.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1584979200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586381100.04481, "questionText": "What is the difference between self-quarantine, self-isolation, and social distancing?", "answerText": "Self-quarantine is staying in place, either at home or elsewhere, for fourteen days because you have been exposed to someone who has tested positive for COVID-19. Self-isolation would be isolating within the house after you start showing symptoms of COVID-19. Social distancing is a response in which people remain home and distant from others (such as by refraining from shaking hands or hugging or going to the store at off hours), without any known exposure to the virus, to limit possible transmission to or from others.", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "66f87498-79df-11ea-a2c2-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "66f8757a-79df-11ea-9c16-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "66f875e2-79df-11ea-a930-8c85901aafa7", "topic": "self-quarantine"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://hub.jhu.edu/2020/03/23/how-to-self-quarantine-self-isolate/?mc_cid=0ed1a231a3&mc_eid=9687fd9d33", "sourceName": "JHU HUB", "sourceDate": 1584979200.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1584979200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586381100.0452962, "questionText": "What are the signs or symptoms that someone should self-isolate? When can the self-isolation end?", "answerText": "If you do develop symptoms, like a fever, cough, or shortness of breath, that is when you would need to self-isolate at home, away from other household members. If you develop these symptoms, contact your medical provider but stay home as long as those symptoms are manageable (like you would for a normal cold or flu). If you have severe shortness of breath or if symptoms suddenly get worse, that is when you should seek out medical care.", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "66f8877e-79df-11ea-84d8-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "66f8881e-79df-11ea-95f0-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "66f88882-79df-11ea-b478-8c85901aafa7", "topic": "self-quarantine"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://hub.jhu.edu/2020/03/23/how-to-self-quarantine-self-isolate/?mc_cid=0ed1a231a3&mc_eid=9687fd9d33", "sourceName": "JHU HUB", "sourceDate": 1584979200.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1584979200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586381100.0457711, "questionText": "What is the safest way to self-isolate one person within a larger household?", "answerText": "If you can have a separate space for the sick person—a space where they can access the restroom without traveling through commons spaces—that would be best. Those who are caring for loved ones who are sick at home should wash their hands frequently, avoid close contact as much as possible, and have the sick individual wear a surgical or procedure mask to prevent droplets spreading through the air. It is also important to clean frequent- or high-touch surfaces, as well to clean clothes in very hot water. Caregivers should also wear a mask, if possible.", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "66f89a02-79df-11ea-9401-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "66f89aa2-79df-11ea-8619-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "66f89afa-79df-11ea-9738-8c85901aafa7", "topic": "self-quarantine"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://hub.jhu.edu/2020/03/23/how-to-self-quarantine-self-isolate/?mc_cid=0ed1a231a3&mc_eid=9687fd9d33", "sourceName": "JHU HUB", "sourceDate": 1584979200.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1584979200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586381100.0463529, "questionText": "In households that are not able to accommodate these suggestions, what else can be done to limit transmission at home?", "answerText": "If you're not a caregiver, maintaining six feet of distance and washing your hands frequently are the main steps, along with cleaning surfaces often. If you are a caregiver, it's certainly tougher. You should wear a mask if possible and follow the other guidelines of handwashing and cleaning clothes and surfaces frequently.", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "66f8b0be-79df-11ea-91bd-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "66f8b15e-79df-11ea-8e52-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "66f8b1b8-79df-11ea-9244-8c85901aafa7", "topic": "self-quarantine"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://hub.jhu.edu/2020/03/23/how-to-self-quarantine-self-isolate/?mc_cid=0ed1a231a3&mc_eid=9687fd9d33", "sourceName": "JHU HUB", "sourceDate": 1584979200.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1584979200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586381100.0467992, "questionText": "How can parents and other caregivers help children and dependents who are unable to follow the recommended advice (like washing hands and not touching your face), particularly if they need to be self-isolated?", "answerText": "I think that's a tougher situation. It's very hard to stay away from kids, especially when they're ill and need care and comfort. If possible, main caregivers should be those who are not at high risk from COVID-19, meaning those not over age sixty or with underlying health issues. Other than that, it's important to take the normal precautions in terms of handwashing and cleaning, but it is much more difficult with children.", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "66f8c228-79df-11ea-86f9-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "66f8c2c0-79df-11ea-ad5c-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "66f8c31a-79df-11ea-8c1d-8c85901aafa7", "topic": "self-quarantine"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://hub.jhu.edu/2020/03/23/how-to-self-quarantine-self-isolate/?mc_cid=0ed1a231a3&mc_eid=9687fd9d33", "sourceName": "JHU HUB", "sourceDate": 1584979200.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1584979200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586381100.04745, "questionText": "How much can caregivers rely on childcare alternatives (relatives, neighbors, babysitters) in this moment?", "answerText": "In general, it's important to keep the circle smaller. At the moment, not exposing yourself to many additional people is best. Healthcare workers, people with critical jobs, and hourly employees who have to work will need to rely on childcare providers. In those situations, you may ask someone you know and trust, and who is reliable in taking the social distancing rules seriously. If possible, childcare providers should not be in a group that's at high-risk for COVID.", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "66f8dbac-79df-11ea-b154-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "66f8dcb0-79df-11ea-9124-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "66f8dd1e-79df-11ea-b677-8c85901aafa7", "topic": "self-quarantine"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://hub.jhu.edu/2020/03/23/how-to-self-quarantine-self-isolate/?mc_cid=0ed1a231a3&mc_eid=9687fd9d33", "sourceName": "JHU HUB", "sourceDate": 1584979200.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1584979200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586381100.048316, "questionText": "What supplies should be on hand, for both self-quarantine and self-isolation?", "answerText": "For self-quarantine you should have your basic supplies like food and thirty days of any medications being taken. If you should become sick, and in anticipation of becoming sick, you should have supplies like Gatorade—something to rehydrate—as well as cough medicine to manage symptoms, and Tylenol to assist with the fever.", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "66f8fd80-79df-11ea-9f8a-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "66f8fe66-79df-11ea-9edb-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "66f8feca-79df-11ea-b582-8c85901aafa7", "topic": "self-quarantine"}
